[
  {
    "question": "Who among the following built a royal road from Indus Valley to Sonar Valley in Bengal to organize and strengthen his empire, which was renamed as GT Road during the British period?",
    "option_1": "Aurangzeb",
    "option_2": "Sher Shah Suri",
    "option_3": "Bahadur Shah Zafar",
    "option_4": "Alam Shah",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "_____ got the Grand Trunk Road reconstructed-",
    "option_1": "Dalhousie",
    "option_2": "Henry",
    "option_3": "Clive",
    "option_4": "Cornwallis",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The tomb of Sher Shah Suri is located in ______.",
    "option_1": "Fatehpur Sikri",
    "option_2": "Delhi",
    "option_3": "Sasaram",
    "option_4": "Agra",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "In _____, Sher Khan (Sher Shah) attacked Bengal and defeated Ghiyasuddin Shah.",
    "option_1": "1358",
    "option_2": "1583",
    "option_3": "1540",
    "option_4": "1538",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the real name of Sher Shah Suri or Sher Khan?",
    "option_1": "Farid",
    "option_2": "Jamal",
    "option_3": "Jalal-ud-din",
    "option_4": "Ambul-Fath",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Humayun was defeated by Sher Shah Suri in the battle of Kannauj in _____.",
    "option_1": "1544",
    "option_2": "1540",
    "option_3": "1542",
    "option_4": "1539",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The silver coins introduced by Sher Shah were also continued by the Mughals in the form of ______.",
    "option_1": "Taka",
    "option_2": "Rupee",
    "option_3": "Tanka",
    "option_4": "Mohar",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following cities was the first city planned by the Mughal Empire?",
    "option_1": "Delhi",
    "option_2": "Fatehpur Sikri",
    "option_3": "Islamabad",
    "option_4": "Agra",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the second battle of Panipat, Bairam Khan defeated ______.",
    "option_1": "Maharana Pratap",
    "option_2": "Khan Zaman",
    "option_3": "Rana Pratap",
    "option_4": "Hemu",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The syncretic religion Din-e-Ilahi (literal meaning - 'Religion of God') was founded by whom?",
    "option_1": "Akbar",
    "option_2": "Aurangzeb",
    "option_3": "Jahangir",
    "option_4": "Babur",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "The platform called Takht-e-Akbari, where Akbar was crowned as emperor, is located in which state?",
    "option_1": "Rajasthan",
    "option_2": "Uttar Pradesh",
    "option_3": "Haryana",
    "option_4": "Punjab",
    "answer": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the meaning of Akbar's thoughts on Sulh-e-Kul?",
    "option_1": "Intolerance towards invaders",
    "option_2": "Universal peace",
    "option_3": "Gender justice",
    "option_4": "Religious equality",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the battle of Haldighati fought?",
    "option_1": "1568",
    "option_2": "1552",
    "option_3": "1576",
    "option_4": "1584",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which queen of Ahmednagar fought against Emperor Akbar?",
    "option_1": "Chand Bibi",
    "option_2": "Razia Sultan",
    "option_3": "Durgavati",
    "option_4": "Roopmati",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "To strengthen the army, ______ started the Mansabdari system.",
    "option_1": "Babur",
    "option_2": "Aurangzeb",
    "option_3": "Akbar",
    "option_4": "Jahangir",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hamida Bano Begum was the mother of ______.",
    "option_1": "Emperor Jahangir",
    "option_2": "Emperor Akbar",
    "option_3": "Emperor Humayun",
    "option_4": "Emperor Babur",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who among the following was not one of the 'nine gems' of Emperor Akbar's court?",
    "option_1": "Usman Ali Khan",
    "option_2": "Raja Todarmal",
    "option_3": "Abul Fazal Ibn Mubarak",
    "option_4": "Fakir Ajio-din",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Akbar's administrative seat was?",
    "option_1": "Allahabad",
    "option_2": "Lucknow",
    "option_3": "Delhi",
    "option_4": "Agra",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Akbar became the ruler of Punjab at the age of........... years.",
    "option_1": "31",
    "option_2": "23",
    "option_3": "13",
    "option_4": "33",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who among the following was honoured with the title of 'Khan-i-khanan'?",
    "option_1": "Akbar",
    "option_2": "Sher Shah Suri",
    "option_3": "Bairam Khan",
    "option_4": "Humayun",
    "answer": "3"
  }
]

